Wyck Association Collection 1663-1972 Mss.Ms.Coll.52
American Philosophical Society
- Series VII. Memorabilia, 1663-1961; 6.5 Linear feet 16 boxes
  - Caspar Wistar Haines II
    - Recipes re. garden and household products (Box 237, Folder 91)
    - Re. engineering, mining, et al., 1907-1908 (Box 237, Folder 92)
    - Re. school, c.1868-1874 (Box 237, Folder 93)
    - School report cards, 1868-1874 (Box 237, Folder 94)
    - Songbooks, 1869 (Box 237, Folder 95)
    - Stamps, n.d. (Box 237, Folder 96)
    - Tables: including re. engineering, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 97)
    - Tickets and passes: including railroad passes, c.1880-1904 (Box 238, Folder 98)
    - Train schedules, 1886-1895 (Box 238, Folder 99)
  - Robert Bowne Haines II
    - Addresses, 1925 (Box 238, Folder 100)
    - Design of iceboat by RBH II, 1883 (Box 238, Folder 101)
    - List of donations, 1931 (Box 238, Folder 102)
    - List of songs, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 103)
    - List of stock at nursery, 1918 (Box 238, Folder 104)
    - Membership cards, 1920, 1928 (Box 238, Folder 105)
    - Prescription, 1925 (Box 238, Folder 106)
    - Report of recitations from Haverford College, 1874-1875 (Box 238, Folder 107)
  - Mary Morton Haines
    - Announcement of death, 1928 (Box 238, Folder 108)
    - Autograph album, 1877 (Box 238, Folder 109)
    - Cards: from Japan, 1912-1913 (Box 238, Folder 110)
    - Description of flowers in Japan, 1894 (Box 238, Folder 111)
    - List of passengers, 1892, 1895 (Box 238, Folder 112)
    - Note cards, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 113)
    - Passport, 1903 (Box 238, Folder 114)
    - Postcards of Bowne House, 1920 (Box 238, Folder 115)
  - William Jones Haines
    - Cards, 1881-1884 (Box 238, Folder 116)
    - Directions for travel, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 117)
    - Re. "The Fairfield Cricket Club", n.d. (Box 238, Folder 118)
    - Plan for galvonometer, 1884 (Box 238, Folder 119)
    - Samples from printing press, 1878 (Box 238, Folder 120)
    - School marks, 1878, 1880 (Box 238, Folder 121)
    - n.d.
  - Jane Bowne Haines II
    - Addresses, n.d. (Box 238, Folder 122)
    - Belt, belonging to Lydia J. Wistar, given to JBH II by MVWH, 1907 (Box 238, Folder 123)
    - Calling cards, 1935 (Box 238, Folder 124)
    - Clippings, 1937 (Box 239, Folder 125)
    - Diploma from New York State Library School, 1899 (Box 239, Folder 126)
    - Greeting cards, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 127)
    - Invitations, 1932 (Box 239, Folder 128)
    - Japanese painting from S. Kasai, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 129)
    - Lists of books, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 130)
    - Membership cards, 1926, 1937-1938 (Box 239, Folder 131)
    - Miscellaneous materials, n.d. (Box 239, Folder 132)
    - Miscellaneous materials, n.d. (Box 240, Folder 133)
    - Notes; re. Pennsylvania School of Horticulture, 1929-1935 (Box 240, Folder 134)
    - Re. Philadelphia Leidy Association, c.1886 (Box 240, Folder 135)
    - Postmark collection, 1890-1900 (Box 240, Folder 136)
    - Recipes for food and household products (Box 240, Folder 137)
    - Re. trip westward, 1915 (Box 240, Folder 138)
    - Valentines, 1848 (Box 241, Folder 139)
  - Diedrich Jansen Haines
    - Re. African trip, 1928-1929 (Box 241, Folder 140)
    - Cards incl. for Ella Haines, 1935 (Box 241, Folder 141)
    - Childhood and school, 1879 (Box 241, Folder 142)
    - Clipping re. death of DJH, 1943 (Box 241, Folder 143)
  - Robert Bowne Haines III
    - Address card file, n.d. (Box 241, Folder 144)
    - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 145)
    - Draft of a vibrator for cherry stoner, 1947 (Box 242, Folder 146)
    - Inventory, 1948 (Box 242, Folder 147)
    - Inventory: re. fire in carriage house, 1952 (Box 242, Folder 148)
    - Membership cards, 1944,1961,1966 (Box 242, Folder 149)
    - Miscellany, 1918-1961 (Box 242, Folder 150)
    - Prizes from State Horticultural Society, 1920 (Box 242, Folder 151)
    - School reports, 1910-1914 (Box 242, Folder 152)
    - Stamp collection, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 153)
  - Mary Troth Haines
    - Miscellaneous materials, 1971 (Box 242, Folder 154)
  - Alphabetical File
    - Addresses, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 155)
    - Addresses: "Help of various kinds" (Box 242, Folder 156)
    - Alcott family materials, 1885-1902 (Box 242, Folder 157)
    - Blotters, n.d. (Box 242, Folder 158)
    - Booklet: "Philadelphia," souvenir of Founder's Week, 1908, with related materials (Box 242, Folder 159)
    - Bowne family material, removed from scrapbook, 1872 (Box 242, Folder 160)
    - Bowne family material, removed from scrapbook, 1880, 1904 (Box 243, Folder 161)
    - Bowne family material, removed from scrapbook, 1911 (Box 243, Folder 162)
    - Business cards and calendars, 1912-1927, 1959 (Box 243, Folder 163)
    - Calendars, foreign language, 1891, 1898 (Box 243, Folder 164)
    - Calling cards, 1906-1935 (Box 243, Folder 165)
    - Cards; including Christmas, birthday, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 166)
    - Cards; membership, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 167)
    - Clippings re. family members, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 168)
    - Clipping re. Richard Hartshorne, 1931 (Box 243, Folder 169)
    - Clippings re. Wyck garden, 1930-1932 (Box 243, Folder 170)
    - Clippings re. Windsor chairs and Blue Willow ceramics, 1923 (Box 243, Folder 171)
    - Clippings re. Germantown, 1886 (Box 243, Folder 172)
    - Clippings re. Wyck, 1924-1930 (Box 143, Folder 173)
    - Clippings re. Bowne, Hartshorne, Correa de Serra, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 174)
    - Children's notebooks, n.d. (Box 243, Folder 175)
    - Clippings re. Mary Huston Haines, 1946 (Box 243, Folder 176)
    - Currency, stamps, 1763-1914 (Box 244, Folder 177)
    - Foreign language materials, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 178)
    - Hair; Dr. Caspar Wistar (1761-1818), et al (Box 244, Folder 179)
    - Historical material; "The American Review", article on Wyck and Germantown, 1923 (Box 244, Folder 180)
    - Historical material; "The Beehive", article on Wyck and horticulture, 1925 (Box 244, Folder 181)
    - Historical material re. Germantown, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 182)
    - Historical material; "Germantown", 1923,1927,1928 (Box 244, Folder 183)
    - Historical material; Handsome Homes of Germantown..., 1899 (Box 244, Folder 184)
    - Historical material; House and Garden, re. Wyck, 1902 (Box 244, Folder 185)
    - Historical material; The Mermaid Club, Its Past and Future, 1897 (Box 244, Folder 186)
    - Historical material; Public Ledger, photographs of Wyck barn when residence of Mantle Fielding, 1906 (Box 244, Folder 187)
    - Historical material re. Wyck, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 188)
    - Inscription re. William Penn and William Mead, 1670 (Box 244, Folder 189)
    - Inventories, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 190)
    - Inventory; Wyck books and manuscripts, 1973 (Box 244, Folder 191)
    - Inventory of Wyck furniture, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 192)
    - Inventory of Wyck manuscripts, n.d. (Box 244, Folder 192A)
    - Invitations and announcements (Box 244, Folder 193)
    - Kennedy, Bridget; miscellaneous material, c.1930-1935 (Box 244, Folder 194)
    - Lincoln, Abraham; "The Lincoln Story - Calendar", 1910 (Box 244, Folder 195)
    - Lincoln, Abraham; miscellaneous material re. Abraham Lincoln, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 196)
    - Lists of books at Wyck, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 197)
    - Lists: various, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 198)
    - Menus, 1914 (Box 245, Folder 199)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 200)
    - Miscellany, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 201)
    - Music, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 202)
    - Patterns; knitting instructions quilt pattern, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 203)
    - Pictures; including drawings, printed pictures, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 204)
    - Pictures; Mexican feathers, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 205)
    - Pictures; Mexican feathers, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 206)
    - Place cards; Mexican feathers, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 207)
    - Plans; architectural, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 208)
    - Plans; architectural, n.d. (Box 245, Folder 209)
    - Re. plants and seeds (Box 245, Folder 210)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 211)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 212)
    - Postcards; Japanese, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 213)
    - Postcards of Wyck, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 214)
    - Pressed flowers and leaves (Box 246, Folder 215)
    - Print on silk, "House of Refuge", n.d. (Box 246, Folder 216)
    - Program for Lafayette reception benefiting Morton Boys' Club, held at Wyck, 1913 (Box 246, Folder 217)
    - Programs; including "Feast of Roses", 1902,1941,1945 (Box 246, Folder 218)
    - Programs; including "Founder's Day in Germantown", 1908 (Box 246, Folder 219)
    - Recipes, 1912 (Box 246, Folder 220)
    - Riddles, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 221)
    - Re. school: University of Pennsylvania, Katharine Wistar, 1891 (Box 246, Folder 222)
    - Scrapbook of pictures including engravings, 1840's (Box 247, Folder 223)
    - Scrapbook of postcards, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 224)
    - Scrapbook re. gardening, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 225)
    - Scrapbook materials re. garden taken from folder 225, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 226)
    - Signatures: Christopher Marshall, William Penn, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 227)
    - Sketch book: mechanical drawings, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 228)
    - Re. societies and voluntary organizations (Box 248, Folder 229)
    - Re. travel and itineraries (Box 248, Folder 230)
    - Valentines, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 231)
    - Re. Wyck garden, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 232)
    - Women's Union Missionary Society, 1947-1950 (Box 248, Folder 233)
  - OVERSIZED Memorabilia
    - Certificates; contributions to House of Refuge, Infant School Society, Society for Promoting Agriculture, materials re House of Refuge (Box OS17, Folder 105)
    - Certificate, Department of the Interior, re. Wyck as an historic building (Box OS17, Folder 106)
    - Certificates, marriage (photocopies) (Box OS17, Folder 107)
      - Bowne, Robert and Elizabeth Hartshorne, 1774
      - Cooper, Isaac and Hannah Coat, 1726
      - Cooper, Isaac and Hannah Furthe, 1797
      - Cooper, Joseph and Lydia Riggs, 1688
      - Furthe, Ezra and Hannah Carpenter, 1768
      - Jones, Griffith and Elizabeth Kunders, 1709/10
      - Waln, Richard and Elizabeth Armitt, 1760
      - Waln, Richard and Elizabeth, family information
      - Wistar, Caspar and Katherine Jansen, 1726
        also in VII, 233:1 and VII, 233:2 (in smaller format)
      - Wistar, Thomas and May Waln, 1786
    - Certificate, marriage; Haines, Reuben I and Margaret Wistar (Box OS17, Folder 108)
    - Certificate, membership in Academy of Natural Sciences, Robert Bowne Haines II (Box OS17, Folder 109)
    - Certificate, membership in Franklin Institute, American Flag House, and Betsy Ross Memorial Association, Merchants Fund (Box OS17, Folder 110)
    - Certificates, membership in Sunday School Society, Society for Promoting Agriculture, Caspar Wistar Haines I; certificate of marriage, Caspar W. Haines I and Hannah Marshall Haines (Box OS17, Folder 111)
    - Certificate from Pennsylvania Constitution Commemoration Committee to Jane Bowne Haines II (Box OS17, Folder 112)
    - Certificates, Vice Consul of Mexico appointment, Caspar Wistar Haines II (Box OS17, Folder 113)
    - Diplomas; Haines, Caspar Wistar II from Haverford College and Lehigh University (Box OS17, Folder 114)
    - Diplomas, Haines, Robert Bowne I, 1844; Robert Bowne Haines III, 1919; Robert Bowne Haines II B.S. fr. Haverford (Box OS17, Folder 115)
    - Indentures; Haines Reuben I (blank forms) (Box OS17, Folder 116)
    - Lincoln, Abraham; misc. materials re. AL (Box OS17, Folder 117)
    - Posters, incl. re. "250 Anniversary Celebration" and various garden parties (Box OS17, Folder 118)
    - Notebook re "Diseases of Swine", RH III, 1822-31 (Box PB2, Folder 166)
    - Certificate of Marriage Caspar Wistar and Lydia Jones, 1826 (Box OS21, Folder 137)
    - Certificate of Marriage Robert Bowne Haines I and Margaret Vaux Wistar Haines, 1852 (Box OS21, Folder 138)
    - Certificate of Marriage Robert Bowne Haines II and Mary Huston Haines, 1890 (Box OS21, Folder 139)
    - Scrapbook of clippings; poetry, n.d. (Box PB1, Folder 154)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, c. 1871-1888 (Box PB3, Folder 158)
    - Scrapbook re. Lukens Steel, c. 1889-1890 (Box PB3, Folder 159)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, c. 1810-1818 (Box OS4, Folder 19)
    - Scrapbook of clippins re. stamp collecting probably belonging to D. Jansen Haines, 1897-1935 (Box PB3, Folder 159a)
- Series VIII. Subject file, 10.0 Linear feet 24 boxes
  This series contains printed material collected by the family and reveals business, educational, and religious interests. Most of this material dates to the 20th century.
  This category is organized alphabetically by the predominent subject matter indicated on the folder heading.
  - Agriculture (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture (Box 249, Folder 2)
  - American Institute for Economic Research (Box 249, Folder 3)
  - American Pomological Society (Box 249, Folder 4)
  - American Scripture Gift Mission (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - American Scripture Gift Mission (Box 259, Folder 6)
  - Automobile Society of Philadelphia (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - Battle of Germantown (Box 249, Folder 8)
  - Battle of Germantown (Box 249, Folder 9)
  - Belgian Gospel Mission (Box 249, Folder 10)
  - Berks-Lehigh Cooperative Fruit Growers, Inc. (Box 250, Folder 11)
  - Berks-Lehigh Cooperative Fruit Growers, Inc. (Box 250, Folder 12)
  - Bible Association of America (Box 250, Folder 13)
  - Blue prints (Box 250, Folder 14)
  - Can labels (Box 250, Folder 15)
  - Choate School (Box 250, Folder 16)
  - Choate School (Box 250, Folder 17)
  - Choate School (Box 250, Folder 18)
  - Choate School (Box 251, Folder 18)
  - Church and Mission (Box 251, Folder 19-23)
  - Church and Mission (Box 252, Folder 24-30)
  - Church and Mission (Box 253, Folder 31-34)
  - Circulars and reports (Box 253, Folder 35-36)
  - Circulars and reports (Box 254, Folder 37-42)
  - Circulars and reports (Box 255, Folder 43-47)
  - Circulars and reports (Box 256, Folder 48-51)
  - Colleges, schools, seminaries (Box 256, Folder 52)
  - Foreign language materials (Box 257, Folder 53)
  - Foreign language materials (Box 257, Folder 54)
  - Germantown (Box 257, Folder 55)
  - Germantown (Box 257, Folder 56)
  - Germantown (Box 257, Folder 57)
  - Germantown history (Box 258, Folder 58)
  - Germantown Hospital (Box 258, Folder 59)
  - Germantown Hospital minutes (Box 258, Folder 60-63)
  - Germantown Hospital Minutes (Box 259, Folder 64-65)
  - Haines Gauge Company (Box 259, Folder 66)
  - Haines Gauge Company (Box 259, Folder 67)
  - Haverford College (Box 259, Folder 68)
  - Historical Society of Pennsylvania (Box 259, Folder 69)
  - Horticultural Societies (Box 259, Folder 70)
  - Instruction manuals (Box 259, Folder 71)
  - Inventions (Box 259, Folder 72)
  - Inventions: RBH III (Box 260, Folder 73-76)
  - Kirby-Hawkins Lumber Company (Box 260, Folder 77-80)
  - Kirby Hawkins Lumber Co. (Box 261, Folder 81-83)
  - League of Evangelical Students (Box 261, Folder 84)
  - Lehigh University (Box 261, Folder 85)
  - Libraries and museums (Box 261, Folder 86)
  - Lukens Steel Co. (Box 261, Folder 87)
  - Manuscript: by E. Claussen (Box 261, Folder 88)
  - Mennonite Church (Box 262, Folder 89)
  - New Jersey State Horticultural Society (Box 262, Folder 90)
  - New York State Agricultural Society (Box 262, Folder 91)
  - Nutrition (Box 262, Folder 92)
  - Pamphlets, miscellaneous (Box 262, Folder 93-97)
  - Patents (Box 263, Folder 98)
  - Patents (Box 263, Folder 99)
  - Peace related material (Box 263, Folder 100)
  - Pennsylvania State School of Agriculture (Box 263, Folder 101)
  - Philadelphia Bible Institute (Box 263, Folder 102-105)
  - Philadelphia College of Bible (Box 264, Folder 106-111)
  - Philadelphia School of Bible (Box 263, Folder 112-117)
  - Placemats (Box 265, Folder 118)
  - Quaker Meeting (Box 265, Folder 119)
  - Railroads (Box 265, Folder 120)
  - Rambo Committee (Box 265, Folder 121)
  - St. Alban's Church (Box 266, Folder 122-125)
  - Skyline Orchards (Box 267, Folder 126-132)
  - Skyline Orchards (Box 268, Folder 133-139)
  - Skyline Orchards (Box 269, Folder 140-145)
  - State of Pennsylvania Cooperative Extension Work (Box 270, Folder 146)
  - Tax information (Box 270, Folder 147-149)
  - Tenant house building specifications, Heidelberg, Cheltenham, Pa. (Box 270, Folder 150)
  - Travel literature (Box 271, Folder 151)
  - Wistar Institute of Anatomy and Biology (Box 271, Folder 152-155)
  - Wistar Institute of Anatomy and Biology (Box 272, Folder 156-158)
  - Wyck House (Box 272, Folder 159)
  - Wyck House (Box 272, Folder 160)
- Series IX. Pictorial material, 1761-1958; 5.5 Linear feet 13 boxes
  This series provides a graphic complement to the manuscripts in the collection. Included are prints, original art, photographs, and maps.
  Of interest among the prints are miscellaneous late 18th and early 19th century engravings, including a view of Wakefield Mills, Germantown. Family interest in natural history is reflected in prints of animals and plants. Also notable are prints of the homes of Charles Bonaparte and E. I. Dupont, and of homes in the Philadelphia area.
  The photographs provide documentation of Wyck's interior and exterior appearance from 1871 through 1958. This section also includes photographs of family members who lived after photography became popular. Representations of many family members who lived before the invention of photography are provided in photographs of portraits. A collection of stereoscopic views of the U. S. Centennial at Philadelphia is also contained in this category.
  Maps and plans included in this series provide documentation of 18th and 19th century land divisions in Germantown and Philadelphia. Also included are plans of Wyck before and after its renovation in 1824.
  The material in this section is arranged in three categories: Original Art, Prints, and Photographs.
  The Original Art consists of two parts. The first part is arranged by family name, for example, "Elizabeth Haines Warder, Drawing, 1827." The second part, consisting of unsigned works, is arranged in alphabetical order by the predominant subject of the pieces, for example, "Drawing, Prospect of the Green House."
  The Prints are arranged in alphabetical order by title or predominant subject matter.
  The Photographs are divided into four Categories: the Alphabetical File, Stereoscopic Views, Wyck, and Portraits. Photographs within each category are arranged in alphabetical order by title or predominant subject matter.
  Oversized material is listed at the end of this section and includes blue prints, plans, drawings, photographs, prints and maps.
  - ORIGINAL ART
    - Reuben Haines III: Sketch Book, c.1820-1830 (Box 273, Folder 1)
    - Reuben Haines III: Sketch Book, 1798 (Box 273, Folder 1a)
    - Ann Haines (?): Drawing, n.d. (Box 273, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth Haines Warder: Drawing, 1827 (Box 273, Folder 3)
    - Elizabeth Haines Warder: Sketch Book, 1830 (Box 237, Folder 4)
    - Hannah Haines Bacon: Drawings (Box 273, Folder 5)
    - Hannah Haines Bacon: Drawings "Topography of Pennsylvania" (Box 273, Folder 6)
    - Margaret Haines Stewardson: Drawings removed from scrapbook (Box 273, Folder 7)
    - Robert Bowne Haines I: Sketch by RBH I for JRH, 1839 (Box 273, Folder 8)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines II: Drawing, 1870 (Box 273, Folder 9)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines II: Mexico-Sketches, 1900 (Box 273, Folder 10)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines II: "Drawing Book", 1866-1867 (Box 273, Folder 11)
    - Caspar Wistar Haines: Drawigs, 1866 (Box 273, Folder 12)
    - Mary Morton Haines (?): Drawings, 1870 (Box 273, Folder 13)
    - Mary Morton Haines: Drawing from Japan, n.d. (Box 273, Folder 14)
    - William J. Haines: Drawing, 1887 (Box 273, Folder 15)
    - E.A. Warder: Drawing "Mill", n.d. (Box 273, Folder 16)
    - Alphabetical List
      - Drawings: Alpine flower pictures (Box 273, Folder 17)
      - Drawings: Circles, Squares, Grids (Box 273, Folder 18)
      - Drawings: "House of Bayside" (Box 237, Folder 19)
      - Drawings: mechanical (Box 273, Folder 20)
      - Drawing: "New Harmony Costume" (of Women), March 1, 1829 (Box 273, Folder 21)
      - Drawing: Perspective drawing. Sketch (Box 273, Folder 22)
      - Drawing: "Prospect of The Green House" (Box 273, Folder 23)
      - Drawing: Sketch Book (Box 273, Folder 24)
      - Drawings: Sketch Book, (1820-1840?) (Box 273, Folder 25)
      - Drawings: Unsigned student sketches of hands, facial features (Box 273, Folder 26)
      - Drawings: Miscellaneous (Box 273, Folder 27)
      - Drawings: Miscellaneous (Box 273, Folder 28)
      - Silhouettes, Hannah Haines Bacon, Reuben Haines III, JBH I, Sarah Haines, Catharine Bowne, John S. Haines, Ann Haines, et. al. (Box 273, Folder 28a)
  - PRINTS
    - "Agriculture", fences (Box 274, Folder 29)
    - Agriculture Implements (Box 274, Folder 30)
    - Agriculture Implements, early 19th c. engravings (Box 274, Folder 31)
    - Anatomical engravings of human, boar, horse (Box 274, Folder 32)
    - "Asaphus Katskillii"; "Fossill Elephant Teeth" (Box 274, Folder 33)
    - Biblical Scenes (Box 274, Folder 34)
    - Birds, early 19th c. engravings (Box 274, Folder 35)
    - Chromolithograph - European genre scenes (Box 274, Folder 36)
    - Classical Scenes (Box 274, Folder 37)
    - Classical Subjects (Box 274, Folder 38)
    - Country Life Series Chromolithographs (Box 274, Folder 39)
    - "Don Pedro, The Property of E. L. Dupont Esq." (Box 274, Folder 40)
    - "Divers Petits Paysages Dessines par Le Clerc" (Box 274, Folder 41)
    - "Dove Cottage at Grasmere", 1897 (Box 274, Folder 42)
    - Drawing Manual plates of animals, houses (Box 274, Folder 43)
    - Drawing Studies published by J. Thackara, Philadelphia. (Box 274, Folder 44)
    - Early Views of Wakefield Mills, Germantown (Box 274, Folder 45)
    - "East Indian Leopard" and "East Indian Tiger" engravings cut from Gentlemen's Mazazine (Box 274, Folder 46)
    - English landscape engraved onto mid 19th century stationery (Box 274, Folder 47)
    - Engravings of Caspar Wistar, M.D., (1761-1818) (Box 274, Folder 48)
    - European costumes (Box 274, Folder 49)
    - "Fair Views of a Sculptured Bone...1801," Caricature, blockprint of steamboat (Box 274, Folder 50)
    - Fish, early 19th c. engravings (Box 274, Folder 51)
    - Fragments, Plates of Ancient Art Works (Box 274, Folder 52)
    - Fragments, Plates of Ancient Art Works (Box 274, Folder 53)
    - Fragments, Plates of Ancient Art Works (Box 274, Folder 54)
    - French Genre (Box 274, Folder 55)
    - French Genre and "Parisien Dancers" (?), Late 18th, early 19th c. (Box 274, Folder 56)
    - Frogs, early 19th century Engravings (Box 274, Folder 57)
    - "Gall's Craniology" with guide, early 19c. (Box 274, Folder 58)
    - Hand colored paper lamp shades (Box 274, Folder 59)
    - "House of Refuge" (Box 274, Folder 60)
    - "House of Refuge" insignia (Box 274, Folder 61)
    - Inscribed engravings of home of Charles Bonaparte, Rome; Blenheim House; Chateau de Maintenon (Box 274, Folder 62)
    - Insects, early 19th c. engravings (Box 274, Folder 63)
    - Landscape, scenes from history, Early 19th century (Box 275, Folder 64)
    - Large Eagle (cut out) (Box 275, Folder 65)
    - Maps - Boston (in German) (Box 275, Folder 66)
    - Maps - New York City, n.d. (Box 275, Folder 67)
    - "Natural History" plate of lion, cat, falcon... (Box 275, Folder 68)
    - Orphan's Asylum, Phila.; Second Bank of the U.S.; Philadelphia College of Physicians and Surgeons; N.Y. Orphan Asylum; Norfolk, Va. (Box 275, Folder 69)
    - "Philadelphia Fashions," Godey's Ladies Books, 1831 (Box 275, Folder 70)
    - Plant "Erigeron Canadense" (Box 275, Folder 71)
    - Plants, early 19th c. Engravings (Box 275, Folder 72)